

Rossella Ferrandino

Email: ross.ferrandino@gmail.com

Mobile: +81 080 7742 9151

Portfolio: rossellaferrandino.info

Location: Tokyo, Japan Github: RossellaFer

Experienced in building web applications with vanilla JavaScript, single page responsive layouts and working with complex data structures. Currently working as Shopify Theme Developer at Flagship LLC, Shopify Plus partner in Japan, customising e-commerce stores on Shopify and coding ad-hoc features to fit the clients' business strategies.

Experienced in customer retention, project management and marketing communications within one of the fastest-growing independent cinema chains in the UK. Heavily involved in the improvement of the user experience, especially paid subscribers, on the Everyman Cinema website.

Skills:

ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, CSS Flexbox, Responsive layouts, Email marketing, Social media

English and Italian: Fluent Speaker

Japanese: Basic Knowledge

Mandarin Chinese: Basic Knowledge

Professional experience

Everyman Media, London, 01/2012 – 01/2019

FRONT END
DEVELOPER
03.2019 - current

- Customise and update clients' e-commerce stores on Shopify to optimise them for the Japanese market
- Create new pages, templates and assisting project managers in configuring Shopify themes and external apps
- Design and implement system architectures suitable for the clients' requirements
- Thorough testing and debugging skills with browser console and external tools

MEMBERSHIP COORDINATOR

01.2017 - 12.2017

12.2017-01.2019 (remote work)

- Project managed the successful launch of a new subscription membership product, from gathering feedback from existing customers, pitching the proposal to the board of directors, to coordinating the system integration between three different suppliers including a new payment provider.
- Actively collaborated to the design of the membership landing page, providing wireframes proposal to the board of directors and graphic designer with userfriendly and clear interactions.
- Led the switch to paperless membership sign up process and the outsourcing of the membership admin to a third party.
- While working remotely, successfully delivered phase 2 of the membership project and remained the main point of contact for all the membership enquiries.
- Trained the new membership team and progressively handed over responsibilities.

MARKETING AND EVENTS ASSISTANT 11.2014-01.2016

- Oversaw all the private events across 14 venues, from the enquiry stage to the event delivery. Managed an average of 260 events per year with a target of £300.000 exceeded by 30% in 2015.
- Provided information by email or phone to clients, discussing requirements and advising on suitable event locations.
- Issued event quotes and contracts for private hire, ensuring client or agency was charged or invoiced correctly and promptly and that the financial information was properly recorded.
- Ensured effective communication with all those involved in the private events, from circulating the events calendar, briefings and making sure the film content is booked and delivered to the site in time.
- Managed the relationships with clients, agencies and internal teams (operations, technical) at the highest possible standards, and deliver firstclass events that meet or exceed client expectations.
- Administered all aspects of loyalty scheme applications, carrying out database processes and acting as main point of contact for all membership queries for the 10.000 paid members.

Education

School of Oriental and African Studies (SOAS) – MSc International Management (China)

09.2011-06.2013 Focus on international business management and its implications in relation to the Chinese market and culture, including high-level courses in international marketing and Chinese language.

Dissertation title: "Made in Italy" in China: a study on the effects of the Country of Origin image on the distribution choices by Italian manufacturers.

Final grade: Merit

Ca' Foscari University of Venice – Master's degree: Languages and Legal Institutions of Eastern Asia

09.2008 – 03.2011 Focus on Chinese language and the Chinese economy. I also spent 5 months in Shanghai as part of my language curriculum.

Dissertation title: "An analysis of Chinese cosmetic market: integration and adaptation to Chinese reality in the case of L'Oréal Group".

Final mark: 110/110